tesol.org 2019-04-19

# Privacy Policy

Your privacy is very important to us. This policy specifies what information we collect about you when you visit our website and how we use that information. It also tells you how you can limit our use of your information. It applies to all TESOL web properties, including the TESOL website, the TESOL Blog, and the TESOL Bookstore.

We reserve the right to disclose your information where required by law or to comply with a valid legal process (such as a search warrant, subpoena, or court order), to protect TESOL’s rights or property, or to ensure users’ safety.

## What Information Does TESOL Collect?

When you visit our website, TESOL’s servers automatically collect information about your navigation patterns and your device, including your internet protocol (IP) address, what type of device you’re using (e.g., tablet, desktop, mobile phone), your device’s operating system, the type of browser you use, and the specific web pages that you visited during your connection. None of this information is personally identifiable.

We may also track data such as the total number of visits to our website and the number of visitors to each web page. We aggregate this information with member demographic data in our database and use it to maintain our system and to better understand how our visitors use our site and other services. The demographic data does not contain any information that identifies you personally. Our goal is to ensure that our website and other services are meeting our users’ needs.

When you make a purchase through the TESOL website, we ask you to “sign up as a new user.” During that process, we ask for your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, and your occupational role. We also ask you for a credit card number or some other account number to pay for your purchase. When you join TESOL, we may ask for more detailed demographic information. TESOL does not store credit card or other third-party account information.

## Does TESOL Keep Track of My Continuing Education Units?

We maintain a confidential record of all the TESOL education programs you have completed and the continuing education units (CEUs) you have earned. Your information is stored on a secure server, and we do not share it with third parties. For more information on access, see “How Does TESOL Protect My Information?” below. For more information on how to obtain a transcript, please contact [TESOL Professional Learning](mailto:learn@tesol.org).

## Does TESOL Use Cookies?

Yes. When you sign up as a new user, TESOL’s servers place a cookie on your computer. A cookie is a small piece of text that gives your computer a unique identity, but it does not contain any information that allows us to identify you personally.

Cookies enable us to keep track of your shopping cart when you make a purchase, and they can remember your password for you so that you don’t have to retype it every time you visit the website.

TESOL also uses cookies to gather demographic and other statistical information. We aggregate this information and use it to improve our website and our services.

Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can opt out by changing your browser setting. If you opt out, you can still access most of the TESOL website, but you will not be able to make purchases.

## What Is Remarketing? Does TESOL Use Remarketing?

When you visit a website that has partnered with a specific remarketing advertising network, a small piece of code called a pixel is created and stored on your web browser, usually in a cookie. This special cookie allows advertisers to provide highly targeted ads to website visitors as they browse the internet. The remarketing cookie uniquely identifies a web browser on a specific computer, but it does not identify a person or provide any personally identifying information.

TESOL has partnered with a remarketing advertising network. TESOL does not provide personal information about its website visitors to its remarketing partners.

## How Does TESOL Protect My Information?

Before you send your information to our database, we encrypt it with secure server software so that no one can read it during transit. We also use secure socket layer (SSL) certificates to protect all the information that we collect against unauthorized access.

Only authorized TESOL staff and contractors have access to personally identifiable information in our database, and that access is limited to what is necessary to complete a transaction with you or to carry out other work-related responsibilities. We take the sharing of personal information very seriously, and staff or contractors who violate TESOL’s privacy policy are subject to disciplinary action, including termination.

## Does TESOL Share My Information with Third Parties?

TESOL may occasionally provide, sell, or rent limited data to third parties, including companies that offer products and services for sale to TESOL’s members and customers. This information includes names, job titles, companies or organizations, and main or preferred addresses, but does not include phone numbers, business fax numbers, educational background, or email addresses. However, TESOL or its agents may occasionally send email messages on behalf of third parties. For information on how to opt out of this service, see “How Can I Control and Update My Information?” below.

If you join TESOL, your contact information is available to other members through a password-protected member directory. Only TESOL members, TESOL staff, and TESOL contractors have access to this director. The member directory enables members to establish professional networks, but if you prefer, you can opt out of this service.

TESOL may also share statistical or demographic information in aggregate form with third parties for marketing or research purposes. This aggregate data does not contain any information that identifies you personally.

## How Can I Control and Update My Information?

We encourage you to keep your information up to date. To check or update your contact or demographic information, you can log in to the TESOL website and click on “My Account” in the upper right corner of the page, or you may send an email message to [TESOL Membership customer service](mailto:members@tesol.org), and we will gladly update your information for you.

If you would prefer not to receive notices, updates, or correspondence from TESOL International Association, please contact [membership customer service](mailto:members@tesol.org), and we will remove you from our mailing lists.

If you would prefer that TESOL did not disclose your information to third parties, you can log in to the TESOL website, click on “My Account,” and update your preferences at the bottom of the page, or you may contact [m](mailto:members@tesol.org)[embership customer service](mailto:members@tesol.org). Changes made online may take up to 30 days to go into effect.

## Links to Other Websites

The TESOL website includes links to other websites and resources. TESOL International Association has no control over such sites and resources and is not responsible for the availability of such external sites or resources. TESOL also does not endorse and is not responsible or liable for any advertising, products, or other materials on or available from such sites or resources, and TESOL shall not be held responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with use of or reliance on advertising, products, or other materials on or available from such sites or resources.

We encourage our users to check the privacy policy of other websites before giving them any personal information.

## Revisions to This Policy

TESOL may revise or update this policy at any time. Any revisions or updates will be posted on this page. This policy was last revised October 2018.
